David Dietz Papers
David Dietz Papers
1916-1977
Dietz, David, 1897-
31 linear ft.
Papers of the Pulitzer Prize-winning American science journalist; science editor for the Scripps-Howard Newspapers and science correspondent for NBC News from 1940-1950. Collection includes correspondence and research files, articles, lectures, book manuscripts, and scrapbooks of columns and feature articles on astronomy, atomic energy, and medicine (1916-1977).
149767
Biographical History
David Dietz (1897-1984) was a Pulitzer Prize-winning science journalist and author. He was science editor for the Scripps-Howard Newspapers and science correspondent for NBC News from 1940-1950, and was heard on ''Morgan Beatty News of the World'' over 181 stations..
1915 Joined editorial staff-Cleveland Press-until retirement
1918 m. Dorothy B. Cohen. (2 daughters, 1 son) 1918 Private, U. S. Army
1919 B. A. Western Reserve University
1921 Science Editor, Scripps-Howard Newspapers until retirement
1927 (to late 1970's) lecturer in general science, Western Reserve
1931 Published Story of science
1937 Pulitzer Prize for journalism
1937 Published Medical magic
1940 B. F. Goodrich Award for distinguished public service
1940-1946 Member Publicity Committee, National Research Council, Division of Medical Science
1942 Member, Harvard University Institute on War Problems
1944-1947 Consultant. to Surgeon General, U. S. Army
1945 U. S. War Department, Certificate of Appreciation
1945 Published Atomic energy in the coming era
1945-1976 President, Shaker Heights Public Library Board of Trustees
1946 Westinghouse Distinguished Science Writers Award
1946 Article "Atomic Bomb", Encyclopedia Britannica, 1946 ed.
1946-1956 Articles on atomic energy, Britannica Book of the Year
1948 Hon. Litt: D. Western Reserve
1954 Hon LLD Bowling Green State University
1954 Lasker Award for medical journalism
1954 Published Atomic Science, bombs and power
1958 Ohioana Career Medal
1958 Published All about satellites and space ships
1960 Published All about great medical discoveries
1961 James T. Grady Award, American Chemical Society
1965 Published All about the universe
1969 Published Stars and the universe
1972 Published New outline of science
1977 Retired
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The David Dietz Papers consists of correspondence, biographical material, writings, and memorabilia.
Correspondence includes some subject folders (e.g. Africa, diesel progress, and Mexico). The correspondence covers Mr. Dietz's long career as columnist and science editor, consequently the list includes personal names, organizations, and businesses. The files retain name and topic headings and contents as Mr. Dietz used them during his career, with the minor exception that titles (Dr., Rabbi, etc) have been consistently moved to follow the person's name.
Biographical material consists of a short autobiography, and a series of autobiographical columns written in 1973 for the Cleveland Press.
Writings consists of articles, lectures and books; each category has been arranged in alphabetical order. In box 29 there is a single folder containing an unpublished, untitled article which requires the permission of Mr. Dietz for perusal.
More than 75 Scrapbooks contain columns written by Mr. Dietz. Several of these pertain to specific subjects; of particular interest are those in packages 11-14 pertaining to atomic energy and its development.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically. Later additions are in boxes 26-29 but are listed in the appropriate location in the finding aid. Writings are arranged alphabetically by type and then by title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Science and medicine; Dietz, David, 1897- Archives.; Jews, American.; Journalism.; Journalism, Medical.; Journalism, Scientific.; Journalists, United States.; Newspapers, Sections, columns, etc.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Lectures.; Manuscripts for publication.; Newspaper columns.; Scrapbooks.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - A, general (Box 1)
  - Abbot, C. G. (Dr.) (Box 1)
  - Abbott Laboratories (Box 1)
  - Abbott Laboratory (Box 1)
  - Abel, Richard (Box 26)
  - Abell, George O. (Dr.) (Box 26)
  - Academy of Medicine of Cleveland (Box 1)
  - Acheson, Dean (Box 26)
  - Adams, Charles E. (Box 1)
  - Adams, Walter (Box 1)
  - Adelhert College Campaign (Box 1)
  - Adelstein, Stanley I. (Box 1)
  - Adler, Norbert (Box 26)
  - Adult Education Association (Box 1)
  - Aebersold, Paul C. (Dr.) (Box 1)
  - AFG Literary Agency (Box 1)
  - Africa (Box 1)
  - Alber, Louis J. (Dr.) (Box 1)
  - Alber, Margaret (Mrs. Louis J.) (Box 26)
  - Albright, John G. (Dr.) (Box 1)
  - Albright, John G. (Dr.), additional material (Box 26)
  - Aiello, Mr. Alfred (Box 1)
  - Air Hygiene Foundation of America, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Air Pollution Foundation (Box 1)
  - Akron Times-Press (Box 1)
  - All About Satellites and Space Ships (Box 1)
  - All About the Universe (Box 1)
  - Allen, Forrest (Box 26)
  - Allen (George) and Unwin Limited (Box 26)
  - [W. H.] Allen and Company (Box 1)
  - Allen Travel Service, Incorporated (Box 26)
  - Allergy Foundation of America (Box 26)
  - Alter, Dinsmore (Dr.) (Box 26)
  - Aluminum Co. of America (Box 1)
  - Alvarez, Luis (Dr.) (Box 26)
  - Amber, Julius B. (Box 1)
  - Amberson, William R. (University of Tennessee) (Box 1)
  - America-National, Catholic Weekly Review (Box 26)
  - American Academy of Facial Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery Inc. (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Family Physicians (Box 1)
  - American Academy of General Practice (Box 1)
  - The American Academy of Pediatrics (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 1)
  - American Association-for the Advancement of Science, Cleveland meeting (Box 1)
  - American Astronomical Society (Box 26)
  - American Cancer Society (Box 26)
  - American Chemical Society (Box 1)
  - American Chemical Society, additional material (Box 26)
  - American College Publicity Association (Box 1)
  - American Commission, Weizmann Institute, 1969- (Box 1)
  - American Committee for the Weizmann Institute (Box 26)
  - American Diabetes Association, Incorporated (Box 26)
  - American Drug Manufacturers Association (Box 26)
  - American Geological Institute (Box 1)
  - American Federation of Radio Artists (Box 26)
  - American Heart Association, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Hospital Association (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences (Box 26)
  - American Institute of Physics, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Israel Public Affairs Committee (Box 1)
  - American Jewish Archives (Box 1)
  - American Jewish Committee (Box 1)
  - American Judaism (Box 26)
  - American Judicature Society (Box 1)
  - American Library Association (Box 26)
  - American Lung Association (Box 1)
  - American Medical Association, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - American Medical Center at Denver (Box 1)
  - American Men of Sciences (Box 26)
  - American Museum of Natural History, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box 26)
  - American Philosophical Society (Jed Fiske) (Box 1)
  - American Press Institute (Box 26)
  - American Psychiatric Association, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Psychoanalytic Association (Box 1)
  - American Public Health Association, Incorporated (Box 26)
  - American Rocket Society (Box 26)
  - American Scholar (Box 26)
  - American Society for Metals (Box 1)
  - American Society for Research in Psychosomatic Medicine (Box 26)
  - American-Swedish News Exchange, Inc. (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Kenneth N. (Box 2)
  - Andrews, Clarence A. (Dr.) (Box 2)
  - Andrica, Theodore (Box 26)
  - Angell, L. Gertrude (Box 2)
  - Anti-Tuberculosis League (Box 2)
  - Appel, Mr. George (Box 2)
  - Applied Physics Laboratory (Box 2)
  - [D.] Appleton and Company (E. L. Smith) (Box 2)
  - Areciba Observatory (Box 2)
  - Arizona Daily Star (Box 2)
  - Arizona-Sonora Desert Museum (Box 2)
  - Army Medical Department (Box 26)
  - Arthritis and Rheumatism Foundation (Box 26)
  - Arthur, William B. (Lieutenant Colonel) (Box 2)
  - Asimov, Isaac (Dr.) (Box 2)
  - Association of American Medical Colleges (Box 26)
  - Association of American Publishers (Box 2)
  - Association of Los Alamos Scientists (Box 2)
  - Astronomical League (Box 2)
  - Astronomical Society of the Pacific (Box 2)
  - Astronomy (magazine) (Box 2)
  - Atchinson, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway System, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Atheneum Publishers (Box 26)
  - Atlantic Refining Company (Box 2)
  - Atomic Industrial Forum Inc. (Box 2)
  - August, Garry (Rabbi) (Box 2)
  - Austen, Maybelle (Box 2)
  - Austin, Warren R. (Box 26)
  - Author's Guild (Box 2)
  - Autobiography (Box 2)
  - Autumn Colors (Box 2)
  - Avon Book Company (Box 26)
  - [N. W.] Ayer and Son (Box 2)
  - Ayres, Henri P. (Box 2)
  - B, general (Box 2)
  - Baade, Walter (Dr.) (Box 26)
  - Bach, John L. (Box 26)
  - Bailey, Dean Henry Turner (Box 2)
  - Bain, Leslie (Box 2)
  - Baker, Arthur (Box 26)
  - Baker, Newton D. (Box 2)
  - Bakwin, Harry (Dr.) (Box 2)
  - Baldwin, John D. (Box 26)
  - Baldwin, William H. (Box 2)
  - Ball Lightning (Box 2)
  - Bar Harbor, Maine (Box 2)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer (Box 2)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer, additional material (Box 26)
  - Barth, Ernest Kurth (Box 2)
  - Baruch, Bernard M. (Box 26)
  - Basic Books, Incorporated (Box 26)
  - Battelle Memorial Institute (Box 2)
  - Baxter, (W.R.E.) (Box 2)
  - Bayer, F. H. (Supr., Shaker Heights Schools) (Box 2)
  - Beacon Press (Box 26)
  - Beck, Claude S. (Dr.) (Box 2)
  - Bedford Democrat (Kenneth E. Crouch) (Box 2)
  - Behrman, Howard T. (Dr.) (Box 2)
  - Bell Laboratories (Box 2)
  - Bell, Eric Temple (Professor) (Box 26)
  - Bellamy, Paul (Box 26)
  - Bemis, William H. (Box 2)
  - Bemisderfer, F. R. (Box 2)
  - Bender, James F. (Box 2)
  - Ben-Dor, Immanuel (Dr.) (Box 26)
  - Benesch, Alfred A. (Box 26)
  - Benjamin, Morris I. (Box 26)
  - Berg, Roland H. (Box 26)
  - Berkner, L. V. (Dr.) (Box 26)
  - [M.] Berkowitz and Company, Incorporated (Box 2)
  - Berland, Theodore (Box 2)
  - Berman, Louis (Dr.) (Box 2)
  - Bernays, Edward L. (Box 26)
  - Bernholm, Bernt (Box 2)
  - Berry, J. Ralph (Box 2)
  - Bertello, Frank (Box 2)
  - Bing, Louis S. (Box 26)
  - Bingham, R. E. (Box 2)
  - Bingham, Robert (Box 26)
  - Binkley, George W. (Dr.) (Box 26)
  - Biological Photographic Association (Box 2)
  - Bishop, Jr., Robert H. (Box 2)
  - Biskind, Leonard H. (Dr.) (Box 2)
  - Blakeslee, Alton & Blakeslee, Alton L. (Box 2)
  - Blakeslee, Howard (Box 2)
  - Blakeslee, Howard, additional material (Box 26)
  - Bliss,, R. W. (Major General) (Box 26)
  - Bliss, Phillip E. (President, Warner and Swasey Co.) (Box 2)
  - Bloomfield, Pete (Box 2)
  - Blue Cross (Box 2)
  - Boardman, Mr. Thomas L. (Box 2)
  - Board of Education (Box 26)
  - Bobst, E. H. (Box 26)
  - Bodley's Library (Box 2)
  - Bohr, Neils (Dr.) (Box 26)
  - Bok, Bart J. (Dr.) (Box 2)
  - Bolton, Frances P. (Box 2)
  - Bond, R. T. (Box 26)
  - Bonino, Louis (Box 2)
  - Bookatz, Samuel, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Book Fair (Box 26)
  - Booth, Harold S. (Box 3)
  - Borden Company (Box 3)
  - Boston Museum of Science (Box 26)
  - Bourjaily, Monte (Box 3)
  - Bowerfind, E. S. (Box 26)
  - Bowers, Charles A. (Dr.) (Box 3)
  - Bowling Green State University (Box 26)
  - Braccland, Francis J. (Dr.) (Box 26)
  - Bradshaw, Emily, Random House (Box 26)
  - Brandeis University (Box 3)
  - Brandeis University, additional material (Box 26)
  - Breese, Murray (Box 26)
  - Brewer, Basil (Box 3)
  - Bricker, Senator John (Box 3)
  - Breasted, Charles (Box 3)
  - Brickner, B. R. (Rabbi) (Box 3)
  - Brickner, Mrs. Barnett R. (Box 3)
  - Bridges, S. R., Atlanta, Georgia (Box 3)
  - British Consulate General (Box 26)
  - British Information Services (Box 3)
  - Bronk, Detlev W. (Box 3)
  - Brown, Bob (Box 27)
  - Brown, Robert S. (Lieutenant Colonel) (Box 3)
  - Brown, Oscar A. (Box 26)
  - Bruner, Raymond A. (Box 27)
  - Bryan, Wright (Box 27)
  - Buffalo Museum of Science (Box 3)
  - Buffalo Museum Of Science (A. Edmere Cabana) (Box 3)
  - Burch, A. T. (Box 3)
  - Bulkley, Robert J. (Box 3)
  - Burkett, Mr. David Warren (Box 3)
  - Burns, Al (Box 3)
  - Buros, Melvin S. (Box 3)
  - Burton, (Honorable) Harold H. (Box 3)
  - Bush, Vannever (Dr.) (Carnegie Institute of Washington) (Box 27)
  - Byers, H. R. (Dr.) (Box 27)
  - C, general (Box 3)
  - Cady, Bertha Chapman (Ex. Sec. Nature Training Schools) (Box 3)
  - Caldwell, Mr. H. V. Y. (Box 3)
  - California Institute of Technology, 1948-1972; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Margaret (Box 3)
  - Canadian Government Travel Bureau (Box 3)
  - Cantor, H. B. (Carter Hotels Operating Corporation) (Box 27)
  - Carey, Frank (Box 3)
  - Carribean (Box 3)
  - Carl Byior and Associates (Box 3)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology (Box 3)
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Carter, George E. (Box 27)
  - Cartoon Publications, Inc. (Box 3)
  - Catton, Bruce (Box 3)
  - Case Institute of Technology (Box 27)
  - Case Observatory Fund (Box 3)
  - Case W. R. U. (Box 3)
  - Cattell, J. McKeen (Box 3)
  - Cattell, J. McKeen, additional material (Box 27)
  - Caughey Jr., John L. (Dr.) (Box 3)
  - Caverns, Carlsbad (Box 27)
  - Celebrezze, Anthony J. (Box 3)
  - Ceni, Dante (Box 3)
  - Center For Human Services (Box 3)
  - Center for Study of Democratic Institutions (Box 3)
  - Central High School (Box 3)
  - Central High School Alumni Centennial Committee (Box 3)
  - A Century of Progress (Box 3)
  - Cerebral Palsy Associations (Box 3)
  - Ceres, Capt. Frederick (Box 3)
  - Cerf, Bennett (Box 3)
  - CERN (Box 27)
  - Chambers, D. L. (Bobbs-Merrill) (Box 3)
  - Chandler, William G. (Box 3)
  - Charles, Fred (Box 3)
  - Chatham College (Box 27)
  - Chautauqua, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Chautauqua Institution (Box 4)
  - Chemical Abstracts Service (Box 4)
  - Chemical Rubber Company (Box 27)
  - Chicago (Box 4)
  - Chilton (Box 27)
  - Ciba Pharmaceutical Products (Box 4)
  - Cincinnati World Affairs Institute (Box 27)
  - City (contracts, etc.) (Box 4)
  - City Club (Box 4)
  - City Club, additional material (Box 27)
  - City Club of Cleveland (Box 4)
  - City of Hope (Box 4)
  - Clarage, Eleanor (Box 4)
  - Clark, Austin (Box 4)
  - Clark, Austin, additional material (Box 27)
  - Clark, Harold T. (Box 4)
  - Clark, Harold T., additional material (Box 27)
  - Clark, Marguerite (Box 4)
  - Clark, Marguerite, additional material (Box 27)
  - Clark, William S. (Dr.) (Box 27)
  - Clarke, Elbert H. (Box 4)
  - Clarke, Ralph Emerson (Box 4)
  - Class of 1919 (Box 4)
  - Cleary, David M. (Box 27)
  - Cleveland Advertising Club (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Astronomical Society (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Blue Book (Box 4)
  - Cleveland College (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Council on World Affairs (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Electric Illuminating Company (Box 27)
  - Cleveland Engineering Society (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Health Museum (Box 27)
  - Cleveland Wealth Museum (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Jewish News (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Medical Library Association (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Medical Service Association (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Metropolitan Park District (Box 27)
  - Cleveland Museum of Art, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Museum of Natural History (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Music School Settlement (Box 27)
  - Cleveland Natural Science Club (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Newspaper Guild (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Orchestra, Artur Rodzinski (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Pneumatic Tool Co. (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Press (Box 4)
  - Cleveland Public Library (Box 4)
  - Cleveland State University (Box 27)
  - Cohn, Victor (Box 4)
  - Colbert, Ralph A. (Box 4)
  - College Club (Box 4)
  - Colleges and universities, miscellaneous (Box 27)
    See also names of specific universities.
  - Collier, Joe (Box 4)
  - Collier Books (Box 4)
  - Collins, A. Frederick (Box 4)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System (Box 4)
  - CBS-TV (Box 4)
  - Columbia University (Box 4)
  - Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons (Box 4)
  - Columbia University Press (Box 4)
  - Columbus Citizen-Journal (Box 4)
  - Column Review (Box 4)
  - Comments on your book (Box 4)
  - Commerce Club (Box 4)
  - Commission on Chronic Illness (Box 4)
  - Committee for the Celebration of the President's Birthday (Box 4)
  - Committee on Information (Box 4)
  - Commoner, Barry (Box 5)
  - Commonwealth Fund (Box 27)
  - Compton, Arthur H. (Box 27)
  - Compton, Karl T. (Box 27)
  - Conant, James B. (Dr.) (Box 5)
  - Cona, Madeleine Carabo (Box 5)
  - Conniff, Frank (Box 5)
  - Consolidated Book Publishers, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Container Corporation of America (Box 5)
  - Cook, Max B., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Cook, Robert C. (Box 5)
  - [Thomas] Cook and Son (Box 5)
  - Copelin, Robert S., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Corbin, Patrick G. (Box 5)
  - Cornell University (Box 5)
  - Cornish, Gertrude E. (Box 5)
  - Cottis, G. W. (Dr.) (Box 5)
  - Council for the Advancement of Science Writing (Box 5)
  - Council on World Affairs (Box 5)
  - Cousins, Mr. Norman (Box 5)
  - Cousteau Society, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Coward McCann & Geoghegan Inc. (Box 5)
  - Coyne Electrical School (Box 5)
  - Crile, George (Dr.) (Box 5)
  - Crombie, Albert H. (Dr.) (Box 5)
  - [Thomas V.] Crowell Company (Box 5)
  - Cruse, William T. (Box 5)
  - Cull, Francis X. (Box 5)
  - Current History (Box 5)
  - Current History, The Realm of Science (Box 5)
  - Cushing, E. H. (Dr.) (Box 5)
  - Cutler (Professor), Elliott C. (Box 5)
  - Cutler, J. E. (Dr.) (Box 5)
  - Cuyahoga Community College (Box 5)
  - Cuyahoga County Conservation Council (Box 5)
  - D, general (Box 5)
  - Dalton, H. G. (Box 5)
  - Danberg, Nina S. (Box 5)
  - Danaceau, Saul S. (Box 5)
  - Danish Embassy (Box 5)
  - Danish Information Office (Box 5)
  - Dantzig, Tobias (Box 5)
  - Darrow, Karl K. (Dr.) (Box 5)
  - Dartmouth College (Box 5)
  - Darwin, Charles (Sir) (Box 5)
  - David, Frederick A. (Box 5)
  - David McKay Company, Inc (Box 5)
  - Davis, Elmer (Box 5)
  - Davis, Karl E. (Western Reserve University) (Box 5)
  - Davis, Watson (Science Service) (Box 5)
  - Day Jr., Rufus J. (Box 5)
  - Day, Mrs. Thomas E. (Box 5)
  - Dean, Gordon (Box 5)
  - De Harrack, Charles (Box 5)
  - de Marco, D. Frederico (Professor) (Box 5)
  - Denison, Doctor A. B. (Box 5)
  - Dennis, James L. (M.D.) (Box 5)
  - Denny, Ludwell (Box 5)
  - Denny, Ludwell ( The Indianapolis Times) (Box 5)
  - Department of Commerce (Box 5)
  - Detroit Town Hall (Box 5)
  - Dettelbach, Mrs. Arthur H. (Box 5)
  - Devine, Dorothy (Box 5)
  - Dial Press (Box 5)
  - Dickey, Lincoln G. (Box 5)
  - Diesel Progress (Box 5)
  - Dietetic Food Laboratories (Box 5)
  - Dietz, Mrs. Catherine (Box 5)
  - Dietz, David
    - Biographical, personal, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Memos to L. B. S. (Box 5)
      See also Seltzer, Louis B.
    - Photos (Box 5)
    - Recent papers and speeches (Box 5)
  - Dietz, David A. (Box 6)
  - Dietz, David B. (Box 6)
  - Dietz, Earl D. (M.D.) (Box 6)
  - Dietz, Jean (Box 6)
  - Dietz, Margaret (Box 6)
  - Dietz Press Incorporated (Box 6)
  - Dietz Securities (Box 6)
  - [Howard] Dittrick Museum of Historical Medicine (Box 6)
  - Dixon, Bruce D. (Box 6)
  - Dodd, Mead and Company
    - General, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - 1941- (Box 6)
    - A. M. Chase (Box 6)
    - R. T. Bond (Box 6)
    - Edward H. Dodd, Jr., 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Frank Dodd, President (Box 6)
    - Frank C. Dodd (Box 6)
    - Howard C. Lewis (Box 6)
    - S. Phelps Platt Jr. (Box 6)
    - William Whipple (Box 6)
  - Dolan, Joseph (Dr.) (Box 6)
  - Donohue, Stephen T. (Box 6)
  - Doty Jr., Charles E. (Captain) (Box 6)
  - Doubleday and Company, Incorporated (Box 6)
  - Doubleday, Doran and Company (Box 6)
  - Dougherty, Donald C. (Box 6)
  - Dover Publications, Incorporated (Box 6)
  - Dowdell, Willam Dowling, Thomas J. (Box 6)
  - Drucker, Lewis (Box 6)
  - Dublin, Louis I. (Dr.) (Box 6)
  - DuBois, J. John (Box 27)
  - Dubridge, Lee A. (Dr.) (Box 6)
  - Dubrovnik (Box 6)
  - Ducas, Dorothy, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Ducas, Dorothy (Box 7)
  - Duke University (Box 7)
  - Dunning, John R. (Dr.) (Box 7)
  - DuPont (Box 7)
  - [E. I.] DuPont DeNemours and Company (Box 7)
  - DuPont Publications (Box 7)
  - Dustheimer, Oscar Lee (Box 7)
  - [E. P.] Dutton and Company Incorporated (Box 7)
  - E, general (Box 7)
  - East, E. M. (Professor, Bussey Institution) (Box 7)
  - Easterman, Alexander L. (Box 7)
  - Eastern Kentucky State College (Box 7)
  - Eastman, Linda A. (Librarian, Cleveland Public Library) (Box 7)
  - Eastman Kodak Company, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Eaton, Cyrus (Box 7)
  - [T.] Eaton Company Limited (Box 7)
  - Eckstein, Gustav (Box 7)
  - [Thomas A.] Edison Memorial Commission (Box 7)
  - Editor and Publisher, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Educational Expeditions International (Box 7)
  - Egan, Mark (Box 7)
  - Egelson, Louis I. (Rabbi) (Box 7)
  - Ehrich, Edward Price (Box 7)
  - Eide, Randolph (President, Ohio Bell Telephone Company) (Box 7)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 7)
  - Eisenberg, Irving (Box 7)
  - Eisendrath, Maurice N. (Dr.) (Box 7)
  - Eickstein, Rudolf (Dr.) (Box 7)
  - Electro-Motive Corporation (Box 7)
  - Electronics (Box 7)
  - Eliot, George Fielding (Box 7)
  - Ellis, A. Caswell (Dr.) (Box 7)
  - Ellis, Paul F. (Box 7)
  - Elsner, Sidney E. (Box 7)
  - Elyria Business and Professional Women's Club (Box 7)
  - Emeny, Brooks, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Emerson Radio and Phonograph (Box 7)
  - Emory University (Box 7)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Encyclopedia of American Literature (Box 7)
  - Encyclopedia Judaica Research Foundation (Box 8)
  - Energy Research and Development Administration (Box 8)
  - Engel, William (Dr.) (Box 8)
  - Engineering Foundation (Box 8)
  - Ennis, Jean (Box 8)
  - Ensten, Harold V. (Box 8)
  - Euclid Avenue Temple (Box 8)
  - Ewan, Earl O. (Box 8)
  - Ewell, Lynn (Box 8)
  - Ewing, Maurice (Dr.) (Box 8)
  - Eye Research Institute (Box 8)
  - F, general (Box 8)
  - Fabricant, Noah D. (Dr.) (Box 8)
  - Facts on File (Box 8)
  - Feather, William (Box 8)
  - Federal Civil Defense Administration (Box 8)
  - Federation of Women's Clubs (Box 8)
  - Federer Jr., Charles A. (Box 8)
  - Fell, Harold (Dr.) (Box 8)
  - Feiss, Julian W. (Box 8)
  - Feiss, Paul L. (Box 8)
  - Fenn College, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Ferris, Earle (Box 8)
  - Fetterman, Joseph, M. C. (Major) (Box 8)
  - Field Enterprises (Box 8)
  - Field Museum (Box 8)
  - Filene, Edward A. (Box 8)
  - Fillmore, Warren I. (Box 8)
  - Finnie, Janet, 1959-1964; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Finneran, John E. (Box 8)
  - Fisch, Max H. (Box 8)
  - Fischer, Karl (M.D.) (Box 8)
  - Fischer, Louis (Box 8)
  - Fishbein, Morris (Dr.) (Box 8)
  - Fishbein, Morris (Editor, Hygeia) (Box 8)
  - Fles, Barthold (Box 8)
  - Fletcher, William (Box 8)
  - Florence, Italy (Box 8)
  - Flying saucers (Box 8)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization (Box 8)
  - Ford (II), Henry (Box 8)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 8)
  - Fordham University (Box 8)
  - Forman, Jonathan, (M. D.) (Box 8)
  - Fox, Leon A. (Lieutenant Colonel) (Box 8)
  - Fox, Milton (Box 8)
  - Fox, Sidney W. (Dr.) (Box 8)
  - Fraley, Pierre C. (Box 8)
  - Franklin Institute, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Free, E. E. (Dr.) (Box 8)
  - Free Press (Box 8)
  - Freedheim, Eugene H. (Box 8)
  - Freedlander, B. L. (Dr.) (Box 8)
  - Freedlander, Isidore (Box 27)
  - Freedlander, S. C. (Dr.) (Box 8)
  - Freiberger, I. F. (Box 27)
  - Freedman, Eugene (Dr.) (Box 9)
  - Freeman, Ira (Dr.) (Box 9)
  - Freeman, Marilla W. (Public Library) (Box 9)
  - French Embassy (Box 9)
  - French, Winsor (Box 9)
  - Friebolin, Carl D. (Box 9)
  - Friebolin, Carl D., additional material (Box 27)
  - Friedman, Richard (Box 9)